A Guide to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA131
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Laboratory notes, 1928-1974; 6
  - Phosphorylation of LRH (lysine-rich histone), 1970-1972 (Box 58)
    - New experimental notes, 1970 1971 (Box 58, Folder 8)
      - Electron micrographs, 1960-1972; 7; 7 folders
        - Electron micrograph photographs (prints) and negatives of Experiments I - X, 1969 February-1972 May
          - Experiment II Histone removed - polylysine added, 1969 May 13; Total 38 prints; 2 duplicate prints; 68 negatives (Box 61, Folder 2)
            - 3), 6 prints; 1 duplicate print; 15 negatives
            - 4), 2 prints; 12 negatives
            - 5), 5 prints; 5 negatives
            - 6), 6 prints; 6 negatives
          - Experiment III, 1969 July 22; Total 23 prints; 41 negatives (Box 61, Folder 3)
            - 1) Control, 4 prints; 8 negatives
            - 2) Histone removed, 7 prints; 7 negatives
            - 3) Polylysine added, 10 prints; 20 negatives
            - 4) Poly arginine, 2 prints; 6 negatives
          - Experiment IV Thymus, 1969 August 19; Total 19 prints; 28 negatives (Box 61, Folder 4)
            - 4) Arginine-rich histone, then lysine-rich histone, 8 prints; 11 negatives
            - 5) Lysine-rich histone, 5 prints; 9 negatives
            - 6) Lysine-rich histone, then arginine-rich histone, 6 prints; 8 negatives
          - Experiment V Liver, 1969 August 21; Total 8 prints; 23 negatives: 2) 4 prints; 11 negatives; 4) 4 prints; 12 negatives (Box 61, Folder 5)
          - Experiment VI, 1969 November 6; Total 35 prints; 19 duplicate prints; 54 negatives (Box 61, Folder 6)
            - 1) Control, 7 prints; 3 negatives
            - 2) Lysine-rich histone removed, 9 prints; 3 negatives
            - 4) Polylysine, 10 prints; 13 negatives
            - 5) Lysine-rich histone (from condensed chromatin), 2 prints; 10 duplicate prints; 16 negatives
            - 6) Phosphorylated lysine-rich histone (from diffuse chromatin), 7 prints; 9 duplicate prints; 19 negatives
          - Experiment VII ph 5.8, 1969 November 12; Total 12 prints; 13 negatives (Box 61, Folder 7)
            - 2), 2 prints; 1 negative
            - 4), 4 prints; 4 negatives
            - 5), 2 prints; 4 negatives
            - 6), 4 prints; 4 negatives
          - Experiment VIII Addition of phosphorylated lysine-rich histone, 1971 March 25; Total 59 prints; 3 duplicate prints; 54 negatives (Box 61, Folder 8)
            Includes some laboratory notes.
            - 1) Control + 2 ml medium, 10 prints; 9 negatives
            - 2) + ordinary lysine-rich histone, 23 prints; 19 negatives
            - 3) + phosphorylated histone, 26 prints; 3 duplicates of #37,43,44; 26 negatives
          - Experiment IX Addition of phosphorylated lysine-rich histone and of CHO - lysine-rich histone, 1971 July 8; Total 24 prints; 23 negatives (Box 61, Folder 9)
            Includes some laboratory notes. No breakdown noted on negatives as to which category.
            - 1) Blank, 6 prints
            - 2) Prep peak A, 6 prints
            - 3) Phosphorylated, 7 prints
            - 4) CH0, 5 prints
          - Experiment X E.M.C. preparation - add fragments of lysine-rich histone to thymus citric acid nuclei from which lysine-rich histone removed, 1972 May 15; Total 32 prints; 32 negatives (Box 61, Folder 10)
            Includes A.E. Mirsky reprint and plate analyses dated July 11, 1972.
            - 1) Control-lysine-rich histone extr., 4 prints; 4 negatives
            - 2) Lysine-rich histone added 5.0 mg, 8 prints; 8 negatives
            - 3) Add III C1 (3.4 mg) x 10,000, 8 prints; 8 negatives
            - 4) Add 3.5 mg of III C1 + 1.73 mg of III N1, 12 prints; 12 negatives
    - Extraction of histones with alcohol and HC1 from thymus sucrose nuclei; primarily graphs, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 9)
    - Planned experiments, 1971 (Box 58, Folder 10)
    - Preparation of histone IIB and IV, 1972 (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - N-Bromo-Succinamide experiments, 1972 (Box 58)
    Experiments by Bert Silverman under supervision of Alfred E. Mirsky Cleavage of LRH with N-Bromo-Succinamide (NBS); DNase and polymerase experiments; includes related papers.
  - Polymerase experiments, 1972 (Box 58)
    A series of experiments by Bert Silverman under supervision of Alfred E. Mirsky in 6 folders:.
    - DNA polymerase - preliminary experiments (Box 58, Folder 1)
    - DNA polymerase - preliminary experiments DNA/RNA synthesis (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - DNA polymerase I (Box 58, Folder 3)
    - DNA polymerase II (Box 58, Folder 4)
    - DNA polymerase - results of various procedures (Box 58, Folder 5-6)
  - Polymerase experiments, 1971-1973 (Box 59)
    A series of experiments by Bert Silverman under supervision of Alfred E. Mirsky.
    - Addition of LRH and ARH, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Addition of histones; H observations, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - Histone experiments; addition of histones, 1972-1973 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Electrophoresis work, 1971-1973 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - RNA polymerase, 1971 1972 (Box 59, Folder 5)
      Includes related paper.
    - DNA polymerase, 1972 (Box 59, Folder 6)
      Includes summaries of; related paper.
    - Miscellaneous DNA polymerase and Bollum's DNA polymerase (mammalian) experiments, 1972-1973 (Box 59, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous RNA polymerase experiments, 1972-1973 (Box 59, Folder 8)
  - Hybridization work, 1973-1975 (Box 59)
    A series of experiments by Rhea Alterman under supervision of Alfred E. Mirsky in.
    - Tissue culture notes for preparation of labelled DNA for hybridization work with summary, 1973 (Box 59, Folder 1)
      Includes 1 notebook.
    - Tissue culture notes on cells, medium etc., 1973 (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - RNA preps from phenol only method, 1973-1974 (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - RNA preps from phenol/CHC1₃-acetate method, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Rat record - implanting pellets, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - RNA from morphine implanted rats, 1974 (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Solutions, recipes for RNA preps, 1973-1974 1975 (Box 59, Folder 7)
- Miscellaneous collection of photographs and negatives of experimental work; individually identified where possible, 8; 5 folders (Box 62)
  - Album of photographs of electrophoresis of histones - January-November 1967, 1967 January-November (Box 62, Folder 1)
    (See Box 57 for laboratory notes on Nonhistone chromatin protein-1967 pertaining to these photographs).
  - Photographs and negatives from various workers in 17 envelopes with description on each (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - 1 photomicrograph of chromosomes in human testes supplied by Jack Schultz, 1946 July 1 (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - 2 negatives of electron microscope assembly (Box 62, Folder 4)
    (See Scientific Reports of RIMR Volume XVI, 1927-28 page 206 for photograph with description).
  - 11 photographic prints of chromosomes in various phases supplied by A.H. Sparrow, Brookhaven National Laboratories, Upton, NY, 1953 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    (See Alfred E. Mirsky "The Chemistry of Heredity" Scientific American 188 (1953) 47-57).
- Slides, 9
  - Slide index on cards filed alphabetically within categories then numerically; slide index in black notebook in numerical order (index to slides in 6 metal boxes 63a, b,c,d,e,f); miscellaneous slides and negatives with inventory and identification on each envelope where possible (Box 63)
    - 4 large envelopes
    - 22 small envelopes' bound together
    - untitled
      3 additional small envelopes each containing a slide box with 2 x 2 slides.
  - Slides in 6 metal boxes
    All slides arranged numerically. Internal evidence indicates some slides borrowed and not returned. Last 16 slides in Box 63e not indexed or inventoried.
    - Slide numbers 1-150 (Box 63a)
    - 151-300 (Box 63b)
    - 301-450 (Box 63c)
    - 451-600 (Box 63d)
    - 601-693 (Box 63e)
    - Duplicates (Box 63)
- Photographic negatives of scientific work, 10; 154 envelopes
  Arranged in chronological order (consecutive numbering for filing).
  - Photographic negatives of scientific work, 10 (Box 64)
- Engraving plates, 1960-1968; 11; 95 engraving plates of illustrations mounted on wood blocks. Individually wrapped by citation information.
  Used in Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences 1960-1968.
  - 9 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 49 (1963) 544-551 (Box 65)
  - 4 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 55 (1966) 358-365 (Box 65)
  - 5 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 55 (1966) 1182-1189 (Box 65)
  - 4 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 56 (1966) 550-557 (Box 65)
  - 6 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 56 (1966) 856-863 (Box 65)
  - 8 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 60 (1968) 152-159 (Box 65)
  - 3 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 61 (1968) 592-597 (Box 65)
  - 2 engraving plates; PNAS reference: Unidentified (Box 65)
  - 11 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 46 (1960) 432-444 (Box 66)
  - 2 engraving plates; PNAS reference: engraving plates; PNAS reference: 48 (1962) 853-859 (Box 66)
  - 3 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 48 (1962) 1590-1596 (Box 66)
  - 3 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 49 (1963) 53-60 (Box 66)
  - 5 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 54 (1965) 696-704 (Box 66)
  - 3 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 55 (1966) 805-812 (Box 66)
  - 16 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 47 (1961) 907-932 (Box 67)
  - 5 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 50 (1963) 1026-1032 (Box 67)
  - 2 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 57 (1967) 743-750 (Box 67)
  - 4 engraving plates; PNAS reference: 57 (1967) 885-892 (Box 67)
- Laboratory memorabilia, 12; Individually wrapped and identified
  - Laboratory memorabilia, 7 packages (Box 68)
    - Quartz microcells, 1 plastic container
    - Quartz slide, 1 cardboard box
    - Zeiss microscope eye pieces (old model - not usable), 1 package
    - Set of test tubes with rack; some of the test tubes with ground glass tops, 1 package
    - Set of Quartz spectrophotometer standards, 1 package
    - Samples of nucleic acids from P.A.T. Levene collection, 1 package wrapped cardboard box
      This attribution from P.A.T. Levene as per statement made by A.E. Mirsky to Bert Silverman. Identified by B. Silverman on August 13, 1974. (Some samples have name "Levene" on them).
    - Set of Quartz spectrophotometer cells, 1 package
  - Laboratory memorabilia, 6 packages (Box 69)
    - Quartz test tubes, 1 round cardboard container
    - Quartz optics, 1 wooden box
    - Special Quartz spectrophotometer cell, 1 package
    - Quartz lens and other lenses, 1 package wrapped cardboard box
      Includes descriptive workings of M8778 fluorescent eyepiece.
    - Quartz condenser, 1 package
    - Polaroid filters, 1 package
  - Sample preparations of nucleic acids, DNA, histones, globin, myosin and haemin, 1974 August 13; 11 plastic bags and 2 boxes (Box 70)
    (Includes 1 plastic bag of P.A.T. Levene sample preparations. This attribution from P.A.T. Levene as per statement made by A.E. Mirsky to Bert Silverman. Identified by B. Silverman on August 13, 1974).
  - Oversized material, Package Oversized (Box 70a)
    - 2 graphs from Alfred E. Mirsky bulletin board
    - RNA artwork for 1965 Christmas Lectures given by A.E. Mirsky and V.G. Allfrey
      (see Box 44 for negative of this drawing).
- Collected papers, 5 volumes
- "The Haemoglobin Molecule" (dissertation, published 1926), 1 volume
- Chase, Allan. The legacy of Malthus; the social costs of the new scientific racism. New York, Knopf, 1977. 686p. xviii index
  1 presentation copy inscribed as follows: For Sonia Mirsky, With shared memories of a great and good man. Allan Chase NY 1/9/77.
- Additions to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky Papers
  - Correspondence and employment record, 1925-1974; 1 box (2.5 inches)
    Immediate Source of Acquisition
    Recieved June 1980
    This collection of correspondence was deposited from the Office of Faculty and Student Records. It consists primarily of administrative correspondence between Dr. Mirsky, Simon Flexner, Herbert Gasser, Detlev Bronk and Frederick Seitz. A few items were in correspondence with the business manager.
    Included are a few early pre-employment letters; complete employment history; arrangements made for period of time spent in California at the laboratory of Lineus Pauling and included a typed, signed letter from Dr. Pauling dated December 2, 1935 expressing admiration for Dr. Mirsky. Included are a few handwritten letters from Mrs. Reba Mirsky and some newspaper clippings about Mrs. Mirsky's musical interest and involvement.
    Arrangement
    Arranged chronologically.
    - 1925-1950 (Box 71, Folder 1)
    - 1951-1965 (Box 71, Folder 2)
    - 1966-1974 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of news clippings, 1981 (Box 71, Folder 4)
    Received 19 November 1981
    17 October 1981, RU, New York City, Joint meeting of American Numismatic Society/RU. Leo Mildenberg, "The Work of the Coin Engraver Kimon of Syracuse." A memorial to Professor Alfred E. Mirsky on his 81st birthday.
    - Coin World, Wendesday, 14 October 1981
      General
      p. 3
      re. Mirsky memorial lecture
    - New York Times, Sunday, 11 October 1981
      Srction D., p. 41.
- Additions to the Alfred Ezra Mirsky Papers
  Custodial History note
  Mrs. Sonya W. Mirsky to RU Archives, May-December, 1982.
  - Biographical materials (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Photostatic copy of Alfred Ezra Mirsky birth certificate. Document. Made, 1940 October 5
    - Harvard College, 1918-1922
      Transcript of records. Original and photocopy. Document.
    - Rockefeller University Faculty and Trustee certificate 1971. On becoming Professor Emeritus. Document
  - Correspondence (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - George Sarton (Historian)/A.E. Mirsky. Post card. Giving title of talk to be presented at Harvard, Feb 23, 1921. Invited by A.E. Mirsky to speak. [Information supplied by Sonya W. Mirsky], 1921 February 20
    - R.E. Priestley, University of Cambridge/ A.E. Mirsky. On approval by Board of Research Studies for Ph.D., 1926 October 11
    - Hjalmar Frisk (University of Göteborg, Sweden)/A.E. Mirsky. On conferring honorary doctor of medicine Oct 2, 1954, 1954 August 23
    - Detlev W. Bronk/Alfred E. Mirsky. Congratulations on forthcoming marriage to Sonya Wohl, 1967 June 27
    - George E. Burch/Alfred E. Mirsky. On recovery from illness and advice, 1969 January 15
  - Alfred E. Mirsky student laboratory notebooks
    Some with Mortimer L. Anson. Includes:.
    - Experiments in chemistry, Ethical Culture School, 1917-1918 (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - with M.L. Anson. Experiments, 1923 October-1924 April (Box 72, Folder 4)
    - King's College, Cambridge with M. L. Anson. Experiments, 1924 May-July (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Physiological Laboratory, Cambridge with M.L. Anson. Experiments, 1924 October-1925 May (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Manuscripts
    - Mirsky. "From a biological stan[d]point, the mechanistic theory of life is more acceptable than the vitalistic one". Manuscript. Harvard College. A. Alfred E. Mirsky, 19 March 1919; Section 1a. 15 pp holograph (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Science Stories by A.E. Mirsky, prior to April 1960 (Box 72, Folder 8)
      [No publication information].
      Includes 15 suggested titles with short description for each.
      Also includes manuscripts of following:.
      Diet and Cancer. Typescript 4 pp.
      Explaining the Magic Bullet. Typescript 5 pp.
      An Obstacle in the Path of the Sperm. Typescript 3 pp.
      A Hormone of Aggressiveness. Typescript 3 pp.
  - Photographs and some negatives of Alfred E. Mirsky; Alfred E. Mirsky and Sonya W. Mirsky; Alfred E. Mirsky with others; and of others. [Where identified by Mrs. S.W. Mirsky] (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Ethical Culture School, NY City A.E., circa 1913-1914
      Mirsky, lower right. Group photograph.
    - Ethical Culture School outing, circa 1915
      Alfred E. Mirsky playing the cello. Photograph. ca 1915.
      A.E. Mirsky in a canoe. Prints and 4x5 negative.
      Ruth Pilpel (Brickner) and A.E. Mirsky. Prints and 4x5 negative.
    - Shelter Island, New York. NAS meeting on"The Gene". Group photograph with identification and copy negative, 1949 June
    - University of Göteborg, Sweden. Alfred E. Mirsky receiving honorary degree, Doctor of Medicine, 1954 October 2
      Photographs of actual ceremony.
    - New Delhi, India. A.E. Mirsky, Dr. Das and unidentified other. Photograph, 1963 February 11
    - University of Palermo, Italy. A.E. Mirsky receiving honorary degree, Laureate in Biological Sciences. A.E. Mirsky and Guiseppi Reverberi are identified. Photographs, 1964 April
    - A.E. Mirsky and unidentified others. Photograph, 1964 November
    - RU Library, Welch Hall, main reading room. A.E. Mirsky standing in front of painting of Lavoisier on A.E. Mirsky becoming Librarian at RU. [Painting now hangs in the Wrightsman Gallery of the Metropolitan Museum of Art.] Photographs, 1965
    - London. A.E. Mirsky and some with unidentified others. [Possibly taken at the Ciba Foundation Study Group on "The role of histones in the transfer of genetic information". Mirsky "Chairman's introduction". Meeting honoring W.A. Engelhardt of USSR. Photographs, 1965 December 3
    - RU Christmas Lectures by A.E. Mirsky and Vincent G. Allfrey. Of A.E. Mirsky with high school students. Photograph, 1965 December
    - Palermo, Italy. A.E. Mirsky with others, 1967 September 25-October 14; 4 different group photographs
      Some identified as V.G. Allfrey, G. Reverberi and E.H. Davidson. At 2nd Int'l summer course on advances in experimental embryology. A.E. Mirsky chairman of course on activation of genes in the embryonic development.
    - Convocation. IN A.E. Mirsky's study, Smith Hall, Room 215, 1970 June
      Includes photographs of:.
      A.E. Mirsky and Nimai C. Panda.
      A.E. Mirsky, N.C. Panda and Bert Silverman.
      A.E. Mirsky in robe and cap".
      A.E. Mirsky in robe and cap ( different pose).
    - A.E. Mirsky, N.C. Panda and other unidentified person, 1970 Summer; Photograph
    - Sonya W. and Alfred E. Mirsky, Date?; Photograph
    - A.E. Mirsky and unidentified other, Date?; 5 × 7 negative
    - Japanese scientist. Not identified, Date?; Photograph
    - 1 mounted portrait of A.E. Mirsky, Year?
  - Royal Institution of Great Britain. Lectures Before Christmas 1959. Friday Evening Discourses and School Lectures. 1959-60 Christmas Lectures for Juvenile Auditory. Program. [1959 first year Christmas Lectures on Science for High School Students presented at RU], 1959-1960; Printed booklet (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Conferences, meetings and seminars and manuscripts
    - NYC, Ethical Culture Society. Felix Adler Lecture, 1970 May 21 (Box 73, Folder 1)
      Mirsky "Heredity - environment, interaction and the nature of man".
      Typescript (photocopy) and handwritten outline. [See also Box no 44].
    - NYC. Ethical Culture Society Lecture, 1972 March 19 (Box 73, Folder 2)
      Mirsky "Our genes: heredity and environment".
      Typescript (photocopy). [See also box no 44].
    - NYC, RU Behavioral Sciences Seminar, 1971 February 18 (Box 73, Folder 3)
      - Mirsky "The role of the genome in behavior"
      - [Title from RU Calendar of Events]
      - untitled, Typescript and handwritten outline of lecture
    - NYC. Beth Israel Hospital, 1972 February 19 (Box 73, Folder 4)
      Mirsky "on the interaction between heredity and environment".
      Typescript and handwritten outlines of lecture.
    - NYC. New York Biological Teachers, 1972 October 13 (Box 73, Folder 5)
      Association. Mirsky "Role of genes in behavior".
      Handwritten text and outline; typed outline of lecture.
    - RU seminar on the ontogeny of behavior, 1973 November 13 (Box 73, Folder 6)
      Mirsky "Genetics of behavioral development".
      Handwritten outline only.
      [See also box no 44].
    - NYC, National Association of Biology Teachers Convention, 1974 October 12-14; Partially typed and handwritten text (Box 73, Folder 7)
      Scheduled to speak.
    - NYU (New York University), [undated] (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Mirsky "Title?".
      Outline of possible presentation.
    - Fordham (University), NYC, [undated] (Box 73, Folder 8)
      Incomplete outline of possible presentation.
    - Miscellaneous outline, partial text etc., 1973, undated (Box 73, Folder 9)
      Written material including outlines and partial text some of which may have been for a book - never completed. Includes reprints and TIME Jan 8, 1973 p. 20 article re John Money "Biological Imperatives".
      Material kept in order found.
    - "Brighter Biochemistry", 1924 December; Printed booklet (Box 73, Folder 10)
      The Illustrated Journal of the Biochemical Laboratory, Cambridge, No. 2.
  - 3 oversized photographs, oversize box (Box 74)
    - Ethical Culture School class photograph, undated; oversize box
      Some student and teachers signatures.
      A.E. Mirsky 4th from left, seated.
      Photograph by Sarony, N.Y.C.
    - Ethical Culture School basketball teach photograph, undated; oversize box
      Mortimer L. Anson and Alfred E. Mirsky identified.
      Photograph by White, N.Y.C.
    - A.E. Mirsky in laboratory, undated; oversize box
  - Documents, oversize box (Box 74)
    - A.B. Harvard University Degree, 1922; oversize box
    - Fieldston School of the Ethical Culture School. High school diploma for Jonathan Addis Mirsky (son), 1944; oversize box
    - National Academy of Sciences membership certificate, 1954 April 27; oversize box
    - Deutsche Akademie der Naturforscher membership certificate, 1958 June; oversize box
    - Honorary Degree. Laureate in Biological Sciences, University of Palermo, Italy, 1964 April 23; oversize box
  - Photographs, 1985 August; oversize box, 3 photographs (Box 74)
    Sonya W. Mirsky/RU Archives, August, 1985
    - Michael Mirsky. A.E. Mirsky's father. Photo by Nickolas Muray, New York, 1924; oversize box
    - Frieda(?) I. Mirsky. A.E. Mirsky's mother, [Date?]; oversize box
    - (? ) A.E. Mirsky in RI/RU Library. On appointment as RI/RU Librarian. Photo by Heka, 1965 January; oversize box
      [See: RI Review, Jan-Feb 1965, p. 16 and 17].
  - "La Capella Palatina Di Palermo. I Mosaici" (Box 1)
    1 bound book. Presented and inscribed to Alfred E. Mirsky from Istituto de Zoologia, University di Palermo, 16 Oct 1967. [A.E. Mirsky chairman of course on activation of genes in the embryonic development at the 2nd Int'l summer course on advances in experimental embryology at University of Palermo, Italy.] Program of summer course in book.
  - Diploma. Honorary M.D. From University of Gothenburg, Sweden. Document, 1954; Oversize Pkg.
  - Rhea-Beth Markowitz Alterman dissertation, 21 June 1984 (Box 75)
    (copy). Dedicated to Alfred Ezra Mirsky. Includes a handwritten note by Dr. Alterman to Sonya W. Mirsky re dedication and sending copy of dissertation.
    [Rhea Alterman was an assistant for research in the Alfred Ezra Mirsky laboratory from ca 1971-1974 when Dr. Mirsky died.].
    Received by RU Archives 22 April 1985.
  - Deed of Gift. Sonya W. Mirsky. Antiquities and Oriental Art, The Alfred E. Mirsky Collection, 22 April 1985 (Box 75)
  - Exhibit catalog "The Art of Ancient Greece", 1986 January (Box 75)
    Selections from The Alfred E. Mirsky Collection. by Cynthia Bronson Altman, Art Curator, The Rockefeller University. Exhibit in RU Library.
  - Dr. Martin Carter/RU Archives. (In RU Archives Alphabetical bio file. under: Mirsky, A.E.), 1986 January 15 (Box 75)
    - 2x2 slide of Alfred E. Mirsky of 1973 informal laboratory photograph by Ingbert
    - Dr. Carter lecturer for 1985 Alfred E. Mirsky
    - Christmas Lectures on Science for high school students. Slide used by Dr. Carter in introduction
  - Medical Records - Personal Physician, 1959-1974 (Box 75)